RAED ALTAKI

Mississauga, ON, L5B 0K4,

Phone: (647)270-7755, Email: raed.simon@gmail.com, LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/raed-altaki/,

GitHub: https://github.com/raedaltaki, Portfolio: https://raedaltaki.github.io/react-portfolio/

SUMMARY

Motivated Full Stack Web Developer with strong technical, programming and problem solving skills. Holds bachelor's degree of computer engineering and certificate of coding and web development from University of Toronto. Experience with software development, analytical thinking, and project management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Materialize, MomentJs, DataTablesJs, JSON, XML, XSLT, CSS/JS Frameworks/Libraries

Back-end: Node.Js, Express, inquirer, Jest, bcrypt, handlebars, sequelize, mongoose, MySQL, SQLite mongoDB, SQL, NoSQL, Apollo, GraphQL, JWT, webpack, React, Redux, context API, stripe, chakra-ui, MERN, PWA, TDD, OOP, ORM, MVC, REST APIs, C#

PROJECTS

CurrenSeed | https://github.com/DJ-KARMA/currenseed | https://currenseed.herokuapp.com/

- Online farmer's market which providing easy platform to buy and sell fresh produce and other items locally
- Progressive single page e-commerce app that allows users to sell and buy products
- Tools/languages: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, MERN, mongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS, Redux, Apollo, GraphQL, BCrypt, JWT, chakra-ui, PWA

Date Concierge | https://github.com/raedaltaki/date-concierge | https://raedaltaki.github.io/date-concierge/

- · Date application that will plan indoor and outdoor dates based on the weather, users' location and mood
- The application managed to pull multiple API's for weather, movies, restaurants and location together to bring the main concept and arranging the perfect date.
- Tools/languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Materialize CSS Framework, AJAX, external APIs

Truevia Game | https://github.com/raedaltaki/Truevia-Game | https://mysterious-coast-93940.herokuapp.com/

- A Truevia game where users can test their knowledge in many categories and difficulties then compare and comment on other players scores
- Full-stack web application with both front and back ends that routes to many web pages and retrieve, save and edit data in/from the server database
- Tools/languages: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, AJAX, MVC, ORM, TDD, OOP, REST, Node.js, Express.js, mySQL, sequelize, bcrypt, handlebars

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Co-op Web Developer

Apr 2021 - present

RTS Consulting – Automation – Toronto, Ontario

- Developed dynamic and interactive application that reads all BAPI XML files and display them as tables using XSLT, javascript, bootstrap and, datatablesJS
- Created responsive HTML Email that is sent automatically when data is updated
- Successfully created an application that takes XML file and converts them to SQL create commands using
 javascript and XSLT then runs them in the system

Control & Instrumentation Project Coordinator

Nov 2017 - Jun 2020

Consolidated Contractor Company (CCC) - Kuwait

- Successfully completed instrumentation work in 2 project units within scope, schedule, budget and quality
- Achieved mechanical project completion and pre-commissioning with the loop-checking team with 0 losttime injuries
- Managed project team and project documentation, reports, material take offs (MTOs) and material issue voucher requests

IT Support Engineer

Jun 2014 - Oct 2017

Consolidated Contractor Company (CCC) - Kuwait

- Provided technical support and assistance to more than 100 users in person and via telephone and email within established standards
- Maintained the stability of the network by monitoring and resolving all IT issues in a timely fashion including troubleshooting, incident investigating and root cause analysis
- Successfully completed building the network for site offices including installing racks, servers and switches and pulling the network cables

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate of Coding and Web Development University of Toronto – Ontario, Canada	2021
Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering Jordan University of Science and Technology – Jordan	2014
> Certificates:	
Project Management Professional (PMP) Certified through Project Management Institute (PMI)	2020
Oracle Database SQL Certified Associate (OCA) Certified through Oracle Corporation	2020
Time Management & Management Stress at Workplace Awarded by Project Management Institute (PMI)	2017